<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<part id="understanding-walrus" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Understanding walrus</title>
	<chapter>
		<title>Walrus concepts</title>
		<section>
			<title>Site</title>
			<para>
				A site is the main abstraction. A site holds rubric tree and boxes. One Walrus installation supports many sites - this means you 
				can host several different sites with different hostnames and different languages in one Walrus installation. 
			</para>
			<para>
				A site is characterized by hostname and language. I.e. for every combination of hostname and language a site is created.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Rubric</title>
			<para>
				A rubric is the main content holder. Rubrics have title, abstract and main body, they can have unique urls, you can specify 
				rules when content in rubric becomes visible and invisible, and, most important - rubrics have references to other rubrics, forming
				a tree - like structure. This structure is represented in site menus and sitemap. 
			</para>
			<section xml:id="rubric-display-modes">
				<title>Rubric display modes</title>
				<para>
					<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>NONE</term>
						<listitem><para>Children of rubric are not displayed</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>SIMPLE</term>
						<listitem><para>Children of rubric are displayed in simple list</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>EXPANDED</term>
						<listitem><para>Children of rubric are displayed in a list where child abstracts are visible</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>BLOG</term>
						<listitem><para>Children are displayed in blog mode - full child body is visible</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					</variablelist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Box</title>
			<para>
				A box is means to include arbitrary information to the site - things, that don't go into rubric hierachy, like footer, banner,
				featured links, etc.  
			</para>
			<para>
				Boxes are tied to the visual representation of the site - the templates specify where and which box appears.
			</para>
			<para>
				For the time being it's impossible to create or delete boxes during site operation time. Boxes are defined during 
				site creation phase and cannot be added or deleted later. Of course, you can always do this in SQL directly in database. 
			</para>
			<para>
				Walrus supports a variety of boxes:
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>TextBox</term>
						<listitem><para>A text box containing a title and a body. If needed, the box can be configured to be displayed without a title (for a footer for example).</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>BannerBox</term>
						<listitem><para>A box that can contain one or more banners. Random banner is rendered every time a page loads.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>ImageBox</term>
						<listitem><para>A box that contains one image. You can use ImageBox for site header, logo, etc.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>RubricBox</term>
						<listitem><para>A box, that has a connection to some specific Rubric. This can be used in many different ways - you
						can extract some specific content to the first page, or show a list of rubrics child subrics (think news box).
						</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
			</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Technology stack</title>
		<para>
			Walrus is written in <ulink url="http://www.java.com">Java</ulink> programming language. It's built by adhering to Model-View-Controller architectural pattern implemented using <ulink url="http://springframework.org/" >Spring</ulink> framework. It 
			uses now abandoned but generally awesome <ulink url="https://springmodules.dev.java.net/docs/reference/0.5/html/xt.html">Springmodules XT</ulink> 
			ajax framework, <ulink url="http://www.hibernate.org/">Hybernate</ulink> persistence layer and a combination of 
			<ulink url="http://tiles.apache.org/">Apache Tiles</ulink> and <ulink url="http://freemarker.sourceforge.net/">Freemarker</ulink> for view layer templates.   
		</para>
	</chapter>
</part>